And in conclusion, we have found Apache to be an excellent server for our web applications.
それで私たちのウェブアプリケーションに関してはApacheは最適だと結論した。
Any questions?
質問はありますか？
Yes, I have a question. Why didn't you use Nodejs?
はい、質問があります。なぜNodejsを使わなかったでしょうか？
Nodejs is an event driven non-blocking IO server that can be used to build high performance web applications.
Nodejsとはハイパフォーマンスウェブアプリケーションの作れるイベントドリブン・ノンブロッキングIOサーバ。
That is an excellent question.
それはいい質問です。
We evaluated several alternative web servers and concluded that while options like Nodejs are very interesting
いくつかのサーバを検討したうえ、Nodejsみたいな選択は非常に面白い方法でありながら
Apache meets our needs and has a solid track record.
私たちの使用においてはApacheが有効でなおかつ安定していると判断しました。
But it doesn't have performance.
けどパフォーマンスはありません。
Everybody knows that Apache applications are slow because they use blocking IO and have context switches.
ApacheはブロッキングIOとコンテキストスイッチを利用しているため、アプリケーションが遅くなるのは皆がわかり切っていることです。
That's a commonly held belief that threaded web servers are somehow less performant or scalable and event based servers.
スレッドのウェブサーバがなんとなくイベント系のサーバより遅いとはよく思われいているけど、
In fact, if you measure carefully you will find that both models have similar performance characteristics.
よく測ってみれば両方とも同じパフォーマンスの特徴を持っているいることが分かるはずです。
Threads don't scale, simple as that.
スレッドはスケールしない、それだけだ。
That may have been true 10 years ago, it's not true today.
十年前ならそれはありうるだったかもしれないけど、現代はそうでない。
Nodejs will run circles around Apache because Apache was built before async was discovered.
Apacheは非同期が発見される前に作られたため、Nodejsの方が確実に早い。
This is where I typically stab myself repeatedly in the ears with a fork until I stop hearing you.
ここまで話を聞くとあなたの声が聞こえなくなるまで、耳をフォークで刺したくなるところだね。
I've looked at Node, it uses a single threaded loop that dispatches events to handlers.
Nodeを吟味した、シングルスレッドのイベントループを利用してイベントをハンドラ―にディスパッチしている
It's a proven model that solves some concurrency problems, but at the cost of code complexity.
同期並行性問題に対しての対策なんだけど、コードが複雑になる。
It gives techies like me the control to ring every last CPU cycle out of our servers.
俺みたいなオタクにサーバのCPUサイクルを最後まで使い切るコントロールを与えてくれている
It must feel empowering to be totally responsible for the performance of your application.
完全にアプリケーションのパフォーマンスの責任を負うのが気持ちいいでしょうか？
To be always on the look out for blocking operations that should be split into little pieces,
小さな部分に分解しなければいけないブロッキング・オペレーションをいつも見張ってなければいけない
each perfectly tailored to optimize concurrent through-put
一個づつ同期的スループットを最適化して
all of the complexities of Assembler with the efficiencies of Javascript.
アセンブラーの複雑さにJavascriptの効率部分を引っ付けたようなもんだ。
I'm a total speed junky.
スピーディになりさえなれば
Do you know what this reminds me of?
これで何が思い浮かぶか分かる？
The invention of the transistor?
トランジスタの発明？
It reminds me of the invention of threads.
スレッドの発明を思い浮かぶのさ。
Threading libraries do exactly what you are doing manually.
スレッドのライブラリは今手動でやっているのをその通りやるのさ
They break up pieces of code to be executed intermittently.
断続全的に実行するコードを分解して、
Switching from instructions that are waiting on IO to instructions that are ready to run.
IOを待っている指示から実行可能の指示を切り替えてくれるんだ
But your sequential code stays in tact, you nary call sequential code, that's the code you can read.
けど同期コードはそのまま。同期とは特に呼ぶまでもなく、読めるコードを
But it's slow as a dog.
けどカメほど遅いじゃ
Your async program is like something from a 19th century gothic horror story.
あなたの非同期プログラムは19世紀からのゴシックホラーストリからのものみたい。
Drunk with your own sense of power, you reassemble pieces of code that were once coherent
時分の力で酔って、以前に明確であったコードを組みこみなおして
stitching them together with event loops and callback functions
イベントループとコールバックで縫い付けって
until your monster, grotesque and menacing, is ready to be brought to life in a Javascript VM.
あなたの異様な恐ろしいモンスターがJavascriptVMで生活をもたらす準備ができると
You throw the switch and the  hideous creature awakes, rises and lurches forward.
あなたがスイッチを入れ、するとお前の作った化け物が目覚め、近づいてくる。
You're simultaneously elated and terrified that something so unnatural could work at all.
そしてここまで非自然的なものが動くと同時に恐怖と喜びの気持ちを体験しているうちに
When you've realized what you've unleased, the pure immorality of it,
自分がどこまで不道徳なことをやったかと気づいたときに
your creation reaches out with its blooded mangled arms and strangles you.
あなたの作った化け物は血だらけついた腕を伸ばして首を絞めつける。
But it's fast as hell.
早ければいいや。
If you're willing to suffer complex code for performance, why not write an Nginx module in C?
パフォーマンスの割に複雑のコードが痛くも痒くなければＮｇｉｎｘのモジュールをCで書いたら？
Nodejs is the most bad ass rock star tech to come out since Ruby on Rails.
「Ruby on Rails」が出てからNodejsが一番イケたロックスターテックだ
As much as a I want to be an optimist and look forward to human progress,
人間の進化を楽しみにした者だけ、あなたみたいな人にであうと
people like you stop me dead in my tracks.
それができなくなるのさ
You're a fanatic in the church of technology fashion.
あなたはテクノロジー・ファッション教会の一員だ。
I could present you with fact after fact, after fact that your thinking about asynchronous programming is completely wrong.
あなたが非同期に対する考え方はなぜ完全に間違えているかの証拠をいくら出して意味がない。
But why bother when you equate technology to rock bands,
だってお前がテクノロジーをロックのバンドに例えて、
fancy yourself a software hipster by wearing your node T-shirt and celebrate horrible code?
そしてNodejsのＴシャットを着て気持ち悪いコードも盛り上げるソフトウェアヒップスターとおもっているよね。
Maybe you were cool, hell, maybe you have groupies,
お前は格好よかったかもしれない。あなたを仰いでいる人もいるかもしれない。
but when it comes to knowing what the fuck you are talking about
けどあなたが自分の言っていることを理解しているとは全くもって考えられない。
you have all of the facilities of a parrot that says, "non-blocking" over and over again.
オウムみたいに「ノン・ブロッキング」を言い続けるのがあなたの理解の限界なのさ。
Non-blocking is the secret in the async sauce. With it, you go fast, without it you go slow.
ノンブロッキングは非同期ソースの秘密材料。あると早い、ないと遅い。
Do you know when humans discovered when the world is round?
人類は地球が丸いと発見したのがいつかか分かる？
1492, Columbus sailed the ocean blue.
1492, コロンブスは海の青を航海した
It was 240 B.C. by a Greek mathematician named Eratosthenes.
エラトステネスというギリシャの学者が240年ＢＣ発見したんだ。
He conducted a simple experiment using the length of shadows and the distance between cities
彼は影と市から市の距離を利用した単純な実験を行うことで
to not only prove the earth is round, but also calculate its circumference.
地球が丸いこと証明しただけでなく円周まで計算することができた。
Sounds low tech.
ローテックのようだ。
It was utterly brilliant.
非常に素晴らしだった。
But somehow for one and a half millennia it was common knowledge that the world was flat.
けどなぜか一千年半地球は平だとは常識であった。
Hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of years of raft ignorance.
何百年の一般無知。
How in motherfucking hell does this happen?
なぜこんなことが起こったんのだろうか？
It was you.
お前のようなやつのせいだった。
You, who make claims about thread performance without measuring.
お前が測らずにスレッドのパフォーマンスを主張するから。
You, who claim hacking your code with a machete turning it inside out
お前が自分のコードをマチェッテでハックして裏返して
into a twisted unrecognizable mess will somehow make it go faster.
認識できない形にするとなぜか早くなると思っているから。
You, who spent your time alternating between problems that are already solved and problems that don't actually exist.
お前が既に解決している問題と存在しない問題を切り替えて時間を費やすから。
You are the reason science was set back a thousand years.
科学が一千年遅れたのがお前のせいだった。
The reason we have not cured cancer,
癌の治療を発見しない理由、
the reason we have not solved world hunger.
世界の飢餓を解決していない理由
It's because of you, mother fucker, that we are not all using Lisp.
お前みたいなマザー・ファッカーがいるせいで今我々はLispを使っていないのも
I'm sorry what was that last part again?
最後の部分はなんでしたっけ？
Never mind.
いや何も
Did you just say "Lisp"?
今「Lisp」と言ってなかった？
You misheard me.
聞き間違え
I could have sworn you just said "Lisp".
今は絶対「Lisp」と聞こえた
If there are no other questions this concludes my presentation.
では以上質問がなければプレゼンを終了する